azurewebsites.net 2012-06-04

# Privacy Statement

**Last updated:** May 2012

## Scope

Windows Azure is a cloud services platform that enables you to build, deploy and manage applications and store data across a global network of Microsoft-managed data centers.  It includes a set of developer services that can be used individually or together. 

This notice applies to use of those services, which include Compute, Virtual Machine, Storage, Database (SQL Azure), Content Delivery Network, Service Bus, Caching, Access Control, and any other Microsoft services that display or link to this notice. These services are referred to in this statement collectively as the “Services.”  Preview or beta releases may be governed by different or additional terms (see Preview Releases below).

_**Notice to End Users: All references to “you” or “your” in this privacy statement are to the customers who contract with Microsoft for the Services.   Microsoft’s customers, in turn, may use the Services to develop and host their own services for end users. Any information Microsoft collects or handles in such circumstances is processed by us on behalf of our customer, who controls the collection and use of the information. An end user should direct privacy-related requests to the entity providing a service to the end user. Microsoft is not responsible for the privacy practices of our customers using our Services. **_

## Collection, Use & Sharing of Administrator Data

Administrator Data includes the information collected as part of purchasing the Services or managing billing and contact information for the Services. For example, Administrator Data includes the name, address, phone and email of the account owner and the email of administrators, whether collected at initial purchase or later during your management of the Services.

The privacy practices applicable to Administrator Data are described separately in the [Microsoft Online Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=249050&clcid=0x409).  We may also use Administrator Data in order to:

  * Contact you to provide information for new subscribers, billing and important updates about your subscription, including information about security or other technical issues regarding the Services.  You will not be able to unsubscribe from these communications, as they are considered an essential part of the Service.
  * Contact you regarding a third-party inquiry we receive regarding your use of the Services.  You will not be able to unsubscribe from these communications, as they are considered an essential part of the Service.
  * Complete the SMS challenge required during the purchasing process.  We do not use mobile phone numbers collected during the SMS challenge for any other purpose unless you choose to submit that mobile phone number as part of your contact information. 
  * Additionally, with your permission, we may contact you via phone or email to provide you with promotional offers regarding Microsoft Online Services. You may change your contact preferences in the account management portal.

Additional information on the privacy practices applicable to your Windows Live ID credentials (the username and password you may use to sign in to Services) are described in the [Windows Live ID Privacy Supplement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=249052&clcid=0x409).

## Collection & Use of Customer Data

Customer Data is all the data, including all text, sound, software or image files that you provide, or are provided on your behalf, to us through your use of the Services.  For example, this includes data that you upload for storage or processing in the Services and applications that you upload for hosting in the Services.

We will use Customer Data only to provide you the Services.  This may include troubleshooting aimed at preventing, detecting or repairing problems affecting the operation of the Services and the improvement of features that involve the detection of, and protection against, emerging and evolving threats to the user (such as malware or spam).

We may use statistical data, trends and usage information derived from your use of the Services for the purpose of providing, operating, maintaining or improving the Services as well as any Microsoft products and services used to deliver the Services.

When you submit a support request, Microsoft may collect additional information related to the support incident. Microsoft may retain and use this information to assist in diagnosing further problems with your account, to understand your organization’s needs, or to improve our services or the support experience. Information may be combined with other information from the support of other Microsoft products and services in order to better understand your experience and needs.  After you submit a support request, we may telephone you for a survey regarding your experience with our customer support.

## Sharing of Customer Data

Except as described in this statement, we will not disclose Customer Data outside of Microsoft or its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without consent.

We occasionally contract with other companies to provide services (such as customer support) on our behalf.  We may occasionally provide these companies with access to Customer Data where necessary for their engagement. These companies are required to maintain the confidentiality of Customer Data and are prohibited from using it for any purpose other than that for which they are engaged by Microsoft.

We will not disclose Customer Data to a third party (including law enforcement, other government entity or civil litigant) except as you direct or required by law.  Should a third party contact us with a demand for Customer Data, we will attempt to redirect the third party to request it directly from you.  As part of that, we may provide your basic contact information to the third party.  If compelled to disclose Customer Data to a third party, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to notify you in advance of a disclosure unless legally prohibited from doing so.

## Use of Cookies & Information about Your Computer

We may use cookies, which are small text files placed on your hard disk by a web server. Cookies contain text that can be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.  We may use cookies for storing your preferences and settings, for sign in and authentication, to assist in fraud detection, or for site analytics.  Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but you can usually modify your browser settings to block cookies.  Please be aware that if you choose to block cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of our site.

We may also use web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel giffs) or other similar technologies to help deliver cookies on our sites, to let us count users who have visited those pages, to assist in fraud detection, or for site analytics.

Microsoft also collects and uses standard computer information to offer a personalized experience, to assist in fraud detection, to help improve our products and services and to conduct statistical analysis.  Standard computer information typically includes information such as your IP address, operating system version, browser version and regional language settings.  In some cases, standard computer information may also include hardware ID, which indicates the device manufacture, device name and version.

## Security of Your Customer Data

Microsoft is committed to protecting the security of your Customer Data. We maintain technical and organizational measures designed to provide and enable security for the Services. This includes a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

Some data may be particularly sensitive to you or your organization or be subject to specific regulatory requirements. You are responsible for determining whether our security meets your requirements.

For more information, please see the Trust Center or our [Security Overview](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=164799&clcid=0x409). If you have specific questions, please contact Support as described below.

## Location of Customer Data

You may specify the geographic region of the Microsoft data centers in which Customer Data will be stored.  Microsoft may transfer Customer Data within a major geographic region (for example, within Europe) for data redundancy or other purposes.  Microsoft will not transfer Customer Data outside the major geographic region you specify (for example, from Europe to US or from US to Asia) except: (1) where you configure the account to enable this (for example, through use of the Content Delivery Network feature which enables worldwide caching of content, or use of a pre-release feature that does not allow data center region selection); (2) where necessary to provide customer support, to troubleshoot the service or to comply with legal requirements; or (3) for software deployments in Web and Worker roles (but not Virtual Machines), where backup copies of the software deployment package may be stored in the United States regardless of the specified geographic region.  Microsoft does not control or limit the regions from which you or your end users may access or move Customer Data. 

Subject to the above restrictions, Customer Data that we process on your behalf may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, the United States or any other country in which Microsoft or its affiliates or subcontractors maintain facilities, and you appoint Microsoft to perform any such transfer of Customer Data to any such country and to store and process Customer Data in order to provide the Services.  Microsoft abides by the EU Safe Harbor and the Swiss Safe Harbor frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of data from the European Union, the European Economic Area and Switzerland.

## Preview Releases

Windows Azure preview, beta or other pre-release services (“Previews”) are optional evaluation versions of the Services offered by Microsoft to obtain customer feedback prior to general release. This section describes the different or additional terms specific to Previews: 

  * **Administrator Data:**   We may contact you to obtain your feedback about the Preview or your interest in continuing to use it after general release.
  * **Customer Data:**   We may use Customer Data you use with the Preview to improve the Preview and related Microsoft products and services.
  * **Security:** Previews may employ lesser or different security measures than those typically present in the Services. Some Customer Data may be particularly sensitive to you or your organization, and hence may require a level of security that Previews do not provide.
  * **CEIP:**   Previews may enable by default Microsoft’s Customer Experience Improvement Program (CEIP) and require that CEIP remain enabled for the duration of your use of the Preview.  CEIP collects basic information about how you use your programs, your subscription, and connected devices. We also collect information about how each is configured and performing. We use this information to create solutions to common customer problems.  For more information, please see the [CEIP Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=52143&clcid=0x409).
  * **Microsoft Error Reporting Service:**  Previews may enable Microsoft Error Reporting Service by default, and require that Microsoft Error Reporting Service remain enabled for the duration of your use of the Preview. Microsoft Error Reporting Service collects information about problems that interrupt you while you work and about errors that occur behind the scenes.  Reports might unintentionally contain personal information, but this information is not used to identify you or contact you. For example, a report that contains a snapshot of memory might include your name, part of a document you were working on, or data that you recently submitted to a website.  Microsoft uses information about errors and problems to improve Windows operating systems, and the software, hardware and services designed for use with Windows operating systems.  For more information, please see the [Microsoft Error Reporting Service Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=31490&clcid=0x409).

## Contact Us

If you have questions regarding this privacy statement, you may contact us through Customer Support or our Privacy [web form](http://go.microsoft.com/?linkid=4320005&clcid=0x409). Our mailing address is:

Microsoft Privacy   
Windows Azure Platform Privacy  
Microsoft Corporation  
One Microsoft Way  
Redmond, Washington 98052 USA

## Changes to This Privacy Statement

We may occasionally update this privacy statement based on customer feedback or to reflect changes in our products and services. When we post changes, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of this statement. If there are material changes to this statement or in how Microsoft will use your personal information, we will notify you either by posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification.

We encourage you to review this statement periodically to be informed of how Microsoft is protecting your information.
